Antonio Ercole De Luca

Machine Learning & Software Engineer

SKILLS Python SQL **Pandas** Django Docker Selenium **AWS** Google Cloud

Airflow

postgres

- optuna
- prophet
- Bash
- Scrum
- TDD

LANGUAGES

- Italian
- English
- Spanish

CONTACTS:



eracle@posteo.eu

https://eracle.me





PROFILE

I am a Senior Software Engineer, working as a consultant since 2016, having shifted over different roles such as Machine Learning Engineer, Data Architect, Data Scientist, DevOps, and Scrum Master.

I have worked on all aspects of data management such as retrieval, storage, cloud infrastructure scaling, data analysis, and mining; encompassing web scraping, design of relational databases, cloud deployment, RESTful API, and Jupiter Notebook.

In 2019 I took a couple of sabbatical years to get into the world of Statistics & Finance.

During my career, I also contributed to two scientific papers in the field of Web Scraping and Data Visualization.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Molofinance

London, Remote (2022)

Software Engineer

Just joined a freshly launched project developed wth Django and postgres;

- Extending Django admin;
- Review and document past design decisions:
- Bug triage and fixing;
- Add backward compatible changes to RESTful API.

World Food Program

United Nations, Remote (2021)

Software Engineer

In a team of 10+ Software Developers, I worked on the Humanitarian Booking Hub: a platform used by UN agencies employees to book accommodations, car rides, flights and clinic visits;

- I used my Scrum experience to let the team achieve effective daily stand-ups;
- standardized and documented Test-Driven Development practices;
- arranged periodical meetings to spot technical debts in past designs;
- I laid the foundations for e2e testing by introducing Factory boy.

Consultant

Remote (2017 - 2019)

Data Architect

Worked with more than 10 international clients on Upwork.com receiving 5/5 stars as median feedback. Some stories:

- Designed an image similarity search engine with near zero response time, indexing more than 40 000 imgs by using Approximate Nearest
- Reduced client's cloud infrastructure costs by dockerizing a Django app and migrating from Digital Ocean to Google Cloud;
- Built a Django app with 83% testing coverage by using Test Driven Development.

Legalkite Ltd

Zurich, Remote (2016 - 2017)

Back-end Software Engineer

Design of several RESTful endpoints;

Improved 10x REST API response time by translating Django ORM queries into raw SQL queries:

Solved data inconsistency bugs by:

- Refactoring postgres schema;
- Making Elasticsearch a read-replica;

Scaled 100x scraping module by porting it to scrapy and scrapinghub.

SpazioDati

Pisa, Italy (2015-2016)

Machine Learning Engineer

Design of a Human-in-the-loop Active Learning workflow using CrowdFlower API. Increased 2x F1-score in Logistic Regression model used for Named Entity Linking by using Uncertainty Sampling.

Synthema

Pisa, Italy (2014-2015)

Software Developer

Productionize Natural Language Processing steps: Segmentation, Tokenization, POS, Stop Words, Dep.Parsing, NER; (Romanian, Japanese, Chinese and German)

EDUCATION

Bachelors Degree

Università di Palermo, Italy

Financial Mathematics, Finance Theory, Multivariate Analysis, Inference, R Language, Probability.

Masters Degree

Thesis on Natural Language Processing: Applying Active Learning on Entity Linking.

Bachelors Degree

Computer Science University of Pisa, Italy

Thesis on Natural Language Processing:

Document classification using lexical and semantic resources

EU funded (5.6 MIn €) project: CAPER.

(2019 - 2020)Statistics & Data Science

(2011 - 2013)

Data Science and Business Informatics

University of Pisa, Italy

(2007 - 2010)